He Did What He Had to Do.
Hoffa is a crime, history, drama film directed by Danny DeVito.
A portrait of union leader James R.
Hoffa, as seen through the eyes of his friend, Bobby Ciaro.
The film follows Hoffa through his countless battles
with the RTA and President Roosevelt.
James R. 'Jimmy' Hoffa, played by Jack Nicholson.
Bobby Ciaro, played by Danny DeVito.
Carol D'Allesandro, played by Armand Assante.
Frank Fitzsimmons, played by J. T. Walsh.
Pete Connelly, played by John C. Reilly.
Jo Hoffa, played by Natalija Nogulich.
Hoffa is a 1992 American biographical crime drama film directed by Danny DeVito and
written by David Mamet, based on the life of Teamsters leader Jimmy Hoffa.
Most of the story is told in flashbacks before ending
with Hoffa's mysterious disappearance.
The story makes no claim to be historically
accurate, and in fact is largely fictional.
Jack Nicholson plays Hoffa, and DeVito plays Robert Ciaro, an
amalgamation of several Hoffa associates over the years.
The film features John C.
Reilly, Robert Prosky, Kevin Anderson, Armand Assante, and J.T.
Walsh in supporting roles.
The original music score was composed by David Newman.
The film was distributed by 20th Century Fox and released on December 25, 1992.
The film received predominantly mixed reviews and grossed just $29 million against its $35 million budget,
with critics being polarized over Nicholson's performance and criticizing the film's story.
The film explores themes of gangster, 1970s, trade
union, disappearance, detroit, michigan.
The tone is emotional.